{
    "id": "2eb6355941c145ccb67944e0baeebd05",
    "title": "Conjunctions And Prepositions Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "She is both pretty ……………………… intelligent.",
            "description": "The correct conjunction is both...and...",
            "answers": [
                "and",
                "as well as",
                "also"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………… his illness, he has never missed any class.",
            "description": "In spite should be followed by of. ",
            "answers": [
                "In spite of",
                "Inspite of",
                "In spite"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "She is not very talented, ………………………., she is highly successful.",
            "description": "Yet is a conjunction it can connect two clauses. However cannot connect two clauses although it expresses more or less the same idea. ",
            "answers": [
                "yet",
                "despite",
                "however"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "You should not leave ………………………… you are told to.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "as",
                "unless",
                "without"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………….. you watch your diet, you are unlikely to develop serious health problems.",
            "description": "Either if or as long as is possible here. ",
            "answers": [
                "If",
                "As long as",
                "As soon as"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "You needn’t …………………………. for me.",
            "description": "When need is an auxiliary verb, it is followed by an infinitive without to.",
            "answers": [
                "to wait",
                "wait",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………. he was an illiterate, he managed to achieve success through hard work.",
            "description": "Although is a conjunction used to connect two contrasting ideas. ",
            "answers": [
                "In spite of",
                "Despite",
                "As if",
                "Although"
            ],
            "correct": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………….. you are free in the afternoon, we can meet for a coffee.",
            "description": "We use if to express a condition. Unless is similar to if not. ",
            "answers": [
                "If",
                "Whether",
                "Unless"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………….. it was a busy day, I couldn’t even have lunch.",
            "description": "As shows the reason. ",
            "answers": [
                "As",
                "Though",
                "If"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "We shelved the project …………………………….. we could not find a sponsor.",
            "description": "Because is a conjunction. Because of a preposition. It is similar to due to.",
            "answers": [
                "because",
                "because of",
                "due to"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "It has been several days …………………………. I talked to her.",
            "description": "Since shows the starting point. ",
            "answers": [
                "for",
                "since",
                "from"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "As she was ill, I went …………………………… her.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "without",
                "unless",
                "with out"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}